# FE Consulting Services Commu

BTW nummer: 505.615.072 ON 0505.615.072 - RPR Antwerpen

Bank: Belfius, IBAN: BE33 0689 0123 8646 BIC: GKCCBEBB

Personal details

Frank Engelen 07/09/1962

Pulderbos (Zandhoven)

E-mail: frank.engelen1@telenet.be

Tel.: +32 478 78 17 51

Profile

I am a result oriented IT manager with extensive experiences in team leadership. My dedication and perseverance are my strong points to execute assignments successfully.

I have a positive leadership style, focussing on strengths to grow personal and group excellence.

Since November 2014 I am an entrepreneur.

Education

PMI - PMP certified since 2001

1992: PICS (Logistics Management) course

1983 - 1985: French - evening course, LBC - Mortsel

1981 - 1983: Bachelor Informatics, St-Lodewijk - Antwerpen

1980 - 1981: Industrial Engineer, IHAM, Antwerpen

1974 - 1980: Scientific B studies, Xaverius College, Borgerhout

Languages

Dutch: native language

English: excellent Italian: notions

French: sufficient

German: sufficient

Experiences

### FE CS: November 2014 - Now Project Manager

#### November 2014 - Now

Client: Data Support N.V. and Data Support Intl. S.A.

 Project Management for all projects: Implementation of Cloud solutions/ ERP system for small & mid-size companies, applying Agile - Kanban development methodology

#### **September 2016 – June 2017**

Client: Trilations – project for SD Worx

- Project Manager: Implementation of a Service Management solution(Cherwell) for International Employment Services at SD Worx:
  - As of February 2017: all 'Payroll coordinators' (+60) operational in Cherwell
  - o On going integration of the Back-Office team in Cherwell pilot phase

#### February 2017 - June 2017

Client: Trilations – project for the VREG

- Consolidation and analysis of problems caused by the implementation of the Uniek Loket at the VREG, EANDIS & INFRAX
- Liaison between EANDIS, INFRAX and the VREG IT supplier in solving problems
- Providing advice for permanent/structural solutions to solve current problems

#### **April 2015 – February 2016**

Client: Coralius - project for EANDIS

QA & E2E Test Management Services at EANDIS

## HP/EDS 1985 - 2014

#### July 2011 - October 2014 EMEA Java Practice lead / Project Manager

- Team-management: managing 35 Java-engineers and 3 Managers (1 BE, 2 Swiss)
- · Capability development:
  - Realisation of a virtual Java capability within HP EMEA Enterprise Services
  - o Java Governance Board: Board that performs technical oversight of all Java projects
  - HP GIS solution: realisation of an Open Source based GIS platform
  - o Roll-out of Agile Scrum methods (e.g.: HP Agile Manager)
- Project manager: rollout ES Service Platform Java Creation Services & Run-time Services. An integrated
  Java development environment in the Cloud: > 25 projects (= + 90% of all projects)
- Technical responsibility for the execution of all Java/Jee projects. Major clients: Vlaamse Overheid, BNP-Parisbas, Atlas-Copco, Alcatel-Lucent, BEKB, Vodafone & Department for Work & Pensions

#### March 2010 – June 2011 Program Manager

Project description: Assessment of the impact of the DCO (Data Centre Optimization) – server migration program on all applications (>400) maintained by HP for Alcatel Lucent

- Managing of 3 assessment teams (1 EMEA, 1 US & 1 AP)
- · Coordination between all affected teams: DCO team, Application delivery teams, 3rd parties and client

# FE Consulting Services COMMV

BTW nummer: 505.615.072 ON 0505.615.072 - RPR Antwerpen

Bank: Belfius, IBAN: BE33 0689 0123 8646 BIC: GKCCBEBB

#### Experiences

#### October 2009 - February 2010 Project Manager

Project description: Migration of + 130.000 documents to a new Document Management System

- Planning of the transition project that had status red. Determine technical approach how to migrate with minimal impact. Creation of a new project team (planning)
- Development, preparation of the migration (intensive load testing) and execution of the migration (execution)
- Closing the project, dismantling of the team, sign-off transition project (close-down)

#### 2005 - 2009 Technical Delivery Team Manager – Java team

- Team-management: managing of + 90 Java-engineers in de Benelux (in 2008 team extended with German Java-team (+1 manager with 20 Java-engineers))
- · Capability development: Roadmap to increase productivity, quality and technical experiences of the team

#### 2003 - 2005 Project Manager / Operations Manager

Project description: Set-up of the AIP (Acceptatie voor In Productiestelling) organisation for the Flemish Government. The AIP organisation assumes the responsibility to perform a final technical control of new or changed business applications before they are taken in production by EDS/Telindus

- Transition project: In cooperation with PS-Testware
  - o Define and document the AIP processes, guidelines and procedures
  - Staffing of the AIP team installation of the AIP test infrastructure
  - Transition of the SBS test-frame activities to the AIP team
- As of 2004, Operations manager for the AIP organisation

# 1985 - 2003 different roles: Systems Engineer, Supervisor, Operations Manager, Technical Delivery Team Manager within the EDS – GM account & Project Manager within the European RMC organisation

- 2002 2003: Co-Project Manager for the 'European Virtual RMC' (Request Management Centers) scope: rollout of the AVAYA Interaction Center (AIC) in the various RMC's (Nanterre, Bari, Bremen, Mechelen)
- 2000 2002: Technical Delivery Team Manager of the Cyberapps team (Java) and Responsible for het Test Specialist Network (20 members) CMM L-3 initiative
- 1996 2000: Operations Manager van de EDS CE-Service Warranty organisation: operations, maintenance and extensions of the applications for GMIO-Aftersales: NEWS (Claims processing for 31 countries), AWARE (assessment of Claims), RPPR/FFCS (Claims statistics), SAR (Parts Sales Statistics)
- 1993 1996: Supervisor EDS Opel Belgium Systems-Engineering team and Project Manager: implementation of B-SDS for Opel France, Opel Finland en Opel Italia
- 1985 1993: Supervisor, Account Specialist, Systems Engineer EDS Opel Belgium account and Project Manager: Implementation of New Vehicle Billing, Pricing & Fleet system for Opel Belgium. (B-SDS)

### 1983 - 1985 (GM)

Trainee: Helpdesk agent - SCOOP (Stock Control Operations & Ordering Procedure)

#### Skills

#### Functions / Roles

Program/Project & Operations Management

Service Delivery Management

**Team Management** 

#### **Methods and Techniques**

- SLC
- Agile Development (Scrum, Kanban)
- V-Model
- PMBoK (PMI)
- CMMI & ITIL

### Technical skills (\*)

- Programming languages: Java/JEE, Javascript, Cobol (mainframe)
- Tools & Packages: Open Source Frameworks: Spring, Wicket, Struts, Hibernate, JSF, GWT, AngularJS,
- Build tools: Jenkins, Repository Managers: Nexus, Archiva
- Application servers: Tomcat, JBoss, Weblogic
- Version control: GIT, SVN, Starteam
- Testing frameworks: Junit, TestNG, Selenium
- Reporting tools: Jasper Reports
- ITSM/ITIL tools: Avaya Interaction Center, Jira, Landesk, HP Universal CMDB, Cherwell
- IDE: Eclipse. IntelliJ
- DB: Oracle, PostgreSQL, DB2 (mainframe)
- HTML, XML

(\*) passive knowledge / limited experience

# FE Consulting Services Commu

BTW nummer: 505.615.072
ON 0505.615.072 - RPR Antwerpen

Bank: Belfius, IBAN: BE33 0689 0123 8646 BIC: GKCCBEBB

Conferences Devoxx (Javapolis)

ADM - 'e-werken': guest speaker

Others Free time: Ju-Jitsu, travelling & photography

Member of the Board of Directors (Treasurer) and General Technical Director of the Vlaamse Ju-Jitsu federatie

(www.vjjf.be)

Member of the Board of Directors (Treasurer) of the Belgische Ju-jitsu Federatie - Ligue Belge de Ju-jitsu

Chief instructor Ju-Jitsu – Juzando, Zandhoven (www.juzando.be)